<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | Mr. Casals]]></title>
  <link href="http://mrcasals.github.com/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mrcasals.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-27T18:07:48+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://mrcasals.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Marc Riera]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back online!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrcasals.github.com/blog/2012/02/26/back-online/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-26T18:07:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrcasals.github.com/blog/2012/02/26/back-online</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been really long since the last time I wrote a post. A lot of things have
happened since: I started the second semester at university, I got angry with
the educational model they're using there and I'm trying to change it. I started
organizing the <a href="http://baruco.org/">Barcelona Ruby Conference 2012 (BaRuCo)</a> (which looks
amazing, I must say) with the people at <a href="http://codegram.com/">Codegram</a>. I improved my
VIm knowledge. I learned about design patterns and became kind of obsessed with
them. I got an Android smartphone. And I found myself with the need of a place
where to talk about all those things.</p>

<p>But sometimes it's better to get rid of everything to start again instead of
trying to keep something alive. That's what I did with the blog: I had one, but
I didn't use it. Now I find myself with the need of a place to save my thoughts
and things I do... But I couldn't use the older blog. It was too unupdated and I
screwed the repo at some point, so I just deleted it and created a new one.</p>

<p>I don't need a change, I just need to start again. That's why I'm still using
<a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>. Besides, Octopress has implemented some nice features
since the last time I took a look at it, such as separating plugins into their
own system or linked posts, which are still in beta (but I'd love to see them
merged in master). Oh, and I just love writing posts with Markdown and VIm :)</p>

<p>The only drawback I find using Octopress is the lack of themes. I just can't
stand another blog with this layout. Too mainstream, I'd say. So I'll try to
create my own layout for this blog, which will be a funny challenge because I'll
have to design something useful <em>from zero to hero</em> and take a look at Octopress
templating system (about which I could not find any docs... shame on you!).</p>

<p>I'm also thinking about taking a look at Octopress' plugins system, which looks
quite nice and easy to work with. I've already got a plugin in mind related to
Spotify and it will take me to create a gem to work with its API, so three
things in one :)</p>

<p>PS: this reminds me that I have to do a cleanup to me GitHub account... So much
stupid repos there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
